911  有什么紧急情况
9-1-1. What's your emergency?
你好
Hello?
有人在吗
Is anybody there?
你需要帮助吗
Do you need assistance?
你有危险吗
Are you in danger?
卡塞尔  下雨怎么办
Castle, what if it rains?
我们婚礼那天
On our wedding day?
下雨会带来好运
That's supposed to be good luck.
但以防万一  还是找个带室内厅的
But we'll find a venue that has an indoor area,
婚宴地点吧
just in case.
就算找到了完美的地方
Even if we find the perfect place,
-那也得等到十月以后  -十月
- it's not gonna be available until at least October. - October!
丰收的季节  完美
Harvest season. Perfect.
是完美  但那样我爸就不能陪我走向圣坛了
Perfect, except if you want my dad to walk me down the aisle.
他到时要去欧洲进行项目研究
He's gonna be in Europe on the research project.
好吧  那就来个冬季婚礼
Oh. Fine. We'll have a winter wedding.
不是说要在室外举行吗
Didn't we say we wanted to do it outside?
是啊  冻伤可不太喜庆
Right. Yeah, frostbite isn't very festive.
不如明年春天再结婚
How about we get hitched, uh, spring of next year?
要是我想早点结婚呢
And what if I wanna get married sooner? Hmm?
谁能怪你呢
Who could blame you?
你俩真甜蜜
You two are so adorable.
我跟你说
Oh, you know what?
也许我们可以今年夏天结婚
Maybe we could find a venue for this summer.
你要在纽约的盛夏
You want to have a wedding
举行婚礼
in the middle of a new york summer?
不要  你说得对
No. You're right.
我知道了  九月
Oh! I know! September!
不会太冷  不会太热
It's not too hot. It's not too cold.
温度适宜
It's right in the goldilocks zone.
-简直完美  -但我九月的周末
- It's perfect. - It is, except I'll be out of town
都要出城签售小说
every weekend on my book signing tour.
除非我们在周一结婚
So unless we get married on a Monday,
不然九月也不行
September's gonna be tough.
主动给你们点建议
A little unsolicited advice.
你哪条建议不是主动给出的
Do you give another kind?
生命中
In life,
做任何事都没有完美时机这一说
there is no such thing as a perfect time for anything.
不好意思  这算什么建议
I'm sorry, that's advice how?
别等了
Don't wait!
管他呢  现在就去市政厅
Hell, just go down to city hall right now.
你俩彼此相爱  别再光说了
You love each other. Stop talking about it.
行动起来吧
Just do it.
我们会找到一个好日子的  没关系
We'll find a date. It's gonna be fine.
对啊  还是继续找吧
Let's keep-- yeah, looking. Okay.
我不知道  卡塞尔  也许我们要求太高了
I don't know, Castle. Maybe we're being too ambitious.
也许我们是该考虑明年春天
Maybe we should consider the spring of next year.
你不是不想等这么久吗
I thought you didn't wanna wait that long.
我就想随机应变[柔韧]
Nah, I just-- I wanna be flexible.
你已经是了
You already are flexible.
看到我的双关了没
You see what I... did there.
什么这么好笑
What's so funny?
你知道贝克特能把她的...
Well, actually, did you know Beckett can lift her--
-没什么  别说了  -晚点告诉你
- No, nothing. Hello. Nothing. - I'll tell you later.
-不许说  -不说
- No. - No.
死者叫泰德·罗林斯
Well, our victim is a Ted Rollins.
胸口中了两枪
He was shot twice in the chest.
今年20岁  一个人住
He was 20 years old, lived alone,
在二手音像店兼职
and worked part-time at a secondhand record store.
一个卖二手唱片为生的20岁小伙子怎么负担得起
So how's a 20-year-old who sells used records for a living
这样的公寓
own a place like this?
说不通的可不止这一点
This is one of the many things that don't add up here.
比如他为什么浑身湿透了
Like why he's soaking wet?
凶手把泰德·罗林斯的尸体放在浴缸里
The killer left Ted Rollins' body in the shower.
警官到达时  水还是开着的
When the officers arrived, the water was still going.
那是谁报的警
And who called them in?
好问题
That's a good question.
11点50分  制服警员因一通死者手机拨出的
At 11:50, uniforms responded to a 9-1-1 call
报警电话而出警
made from the victim's cell phone.
但死亡时间是8点到11点
But the time of death is between 8:00 and 11:00.
所以不可能是泰德报的警
So there's no way Ted could've placed that call.
凶手射杀了他又报了警
So the killer shot him and then called 9-1-1.
但死者不是在公寓里中枪的
Except our victim was not shot in this apartment.
为什么这么说
How do we know that?
因为他背上有子弹射出口
Because he has exit wounds in his back,
但浴室乃至整个公寓里
but there are no bullets in the bathroom
都没有子弹
or anywhere else in the apartment.
尸斑也显示尸体被人移动过
Plus lividity indicates the body was moved.
凶手把他放在浴缸里冲澡
Okay, so then the killer put him in the shower
好把原始犯罪现场的蛛丝马迹冲刷掉
to wash off the trace evidence from the original crime scene.
差点就成功了  但功亏一篑
And it almost worked except for this.
这里带红点的油脂
The grease here with the tiny red specks?
没被水冲掉
Water didn't get that out.
膝盖和手肘都有
It's on his knees and his elbows.
我猜想是他
I'm thinking he fell
中枪时摔在了这东西上
when he got shot and landed in that stuff.
把这东西送到鉴证科去
Okay, let's get this material to C.S.U.
-看他们能不能查到他在哪遇害的  -真不明白
- see if they can tell us where he was killed. - I don't get it.
凶手为什么要冒险把尸体从犯罪现场
why would the killer risk moving the body back here
搬到这里
from the crime scene?
这案子像
Sounds like a case of
讲述两名保险公司职员一心享受一个毕生难忘的劳动节假期
但在假期中竟然经历了谋杀案  伤人罪及浪漫爱情等
《老板渡假去》出了岔子
"Weekend at bernie's" gone wrong.
不  慢着
No. No, wait.
这么说的话就还有
That would have to mean there's such a thing
不出岔子的《老板渡假去》
as a "Weekend at bernie's" gone right.
等一下
Wait a minute.
两只脚的鞋带绑法不同
These two shoelaces are tied differently.
好奇怪
That is odd.
这更奇怪
This is even more odd.
你干什么
What are you doing?
看来泰德有个暗格
Looks like Ted's got a secret compartment.
没有秘密怎么称得上
And what's a secret compartment...
是暗格
without a secret?
手提电脑
A laptop.
疑团的关键以及凶手的身份
The key to our mystery and the identity of our killer
也许就在这机器里
may lie within that device.
就算是  我也进不去
Well, if it does, I can't get to it.
说真的  我从没见过这种情况
Honestly, I've never seen anything like this before.
这是什么
So what are we looking at here?
一个很高级的加密程序
A very high-level encryption program.
怎么  你不能破解吗
What, and you can't crack it?
拜托  天才少女  我以为你是最棒的
Come on, genius bar. I thought you were the best.
我是
I am.
只是设计这东西的人...更棒
It's just whoever designed this is... better.
给我点时间  让我想想办法
But give me some time. Let me see what I can do.
还有人好奇一个唱片店店员
Anyone else wondering what a record store clerk
怎么会有这种高科技的东西吗
is doing with this kind of technology?
埃斯波  你跟他的家人联系了吗
Espo, did you contact next of kin?
联系了  泰德的父亲和他的弟弟
Yeah, Ted's father and little brother.
他们正赶过来
They're on their way down.
我昨天还和泰德聊过  他怎么会死
I just talked to Ted yesterday. How could he be gone?
罗林斯先生  你昨天跟你儿子聊的时候
Mr. Rollins, when you spoke with your son,
他有没有表现出担忧或害怕
did he seem worried or scared about anything?
他说一切都很好
He said everything was fine.
也许你能帮我们点别的忙
Maybe you could help us with something else.
我们在泰德住处的地板下找到一个笔记本电脑
We found a laptop in one of the floorboards of Ted's place
里面有一个很复杂的加密系统
with a highly sophisticated encryption system.
你们有人知道那是干什么用的吗
Either one of you know what it was doing there?
怎么了
What is it?
泰德是个...电脑高手
Ted was a... computer whiz.
应该说是天才
More like a genius.
但那让他惹上了麻烦
But it got him into trouble.
泰德上高中时  他干上了身份盗窃
When Ted was in high school, he got into identity theft--
窃取信用卡  银行账户之类的东西
hijacking credit cards, bank accounts, stuff like that.
对  他称之为"效仿罗宾汉"
Yeah, he'd call it "Pulling a Robin Hood."
因为他从富人那里偷钱
'cause he would steal from the rich
然后送给穷人
and give to the poor.
穷人是指泰德吗
The poor being Ted?
他那时只是个孩子
He was just a kid.
他总共偷了多少钱
So how much did he end up stealing?
140万美元
$1.4 million.
但法官让他还回去了
But the judge made him give it back.
泰德的认罪协议的一部分就是
Part of Ted's plea deal was that he was barred
他不能使用任何可以上网的设备
from using any devices connecting him to the internet.
所以他不应该有笔记本电脑
So he shouldn't have had that laptop.
有迹象表明他又重操旧业
Is there anything to indicate that he went back
开始进行身份盗窃了吗
to committing identity theft?
我下岗了  然后...
I was laid off, and...
泰德帮我付了格兰特的学费
Ted helped me with Grant's tuition.
我知道他在捣什么鬼
I knew he was up to something.
我只是不愿相信他又开始当黑客了
I just didn't wanna believe he was hacking again.
好吧
Okay, so,
我们假设他又开始盗窃身份了
let's just say he went back to stealing identities.
那能解释他被杀的原因吗
Does that explain why he was killed?
人们身份被窃后的确是会很生气
Yeah, people get pissed about getting their identities stolen,
但通常他们会报警
but normally, they report it to the police.
也许他偷了那些
Well, maybe he stole from the kind of people
不会报警的人
that don't report to the police.
看看是谁休陪产假回来了
Look who's back from paternity leave.
萨拉·格蕾丝怎么样
So how's Sarah Grace?
伙计  我跟你说  她真是...
Oh! Man. I tell you, she is just...
我的完美小天使
my perfect little angel.
她真可爱
Oh, she's so cute.
是我看错还是...她长得很像埃斯波西托
Is it me or--or does she... look a lot like Esposito?
对  没错
Yeah, she does.
真的吗  贝克特
Really, Beckett?
我料到混蛋会说这种话而不是你
I expected that from jackass but not from you.
我把鉴证组的报告拿回来了
Anyway, so I got that C.S.U. report back.
看起来泰德可能是在洗车店被杀的
Looks like Ted might've been killed in an auto body shop.
他有车吗
Did he even own a car?
没有  但他们鉴定了泰德衣服上的泥
No, but they identified that sludge on Ted's clothes.
是混着红色油漆斑点的液压油
It's hydraulic fluid mixed with red paint flecks.
那种油漆是具有大量挥发性有机化合物的
Now the paint is urethane-based with high levels
聚氨酯系混合物  所以很可能是
of a volatile organic compound, so it's most likely
来自一辆90年代前喷漆的车
from a car painted prior to the 1990s.
好  排查泰德家周围的洗车店
Okay, canvass the auto shops near Ted's place.
也许有人在其中一家看到过他
Maybe he was seen at one of them.
贝克特  我们有发现了
Beckett, we got something.
泰德的笔记本电脑就像增强版的诺克斯堡
Now, Ted's laptop is like Fort Knox on steroids.
但托瑞在一个服务器集标识符的注册表中
But Tory found some unscrambled artifacts in the registry
找到了一些译码工具
to a service set identifier.
我也不知道那是什么意思
I don't know what that means either,
但她对此表示很兴奋
but she got really excited about it.
这就是原因
And here's why.
昨天下午7点19泰德连上了一个
Yesterday at 7:19 P.M. Ted connected
私人电脑网络的专用服务器
to a dedicated server of a private computer network.
我追踪了那个网络  它属于...
I traced the network. It belongs to...
通用银行咨询公司
Universal Banking Solutions.
他们的总部在芝加哥  但在全球
They're based in Chicago but have satellite offices
都有办事处  曼哈顿也有
all over the world, including Manhattan,
泰德就是连上了那里
which is where Ted connected.
根据网站的描述  通用银行咨询公司
Now according to the web site, "Universal Banking Solutions
为国际客户处理
handles strategic and tactical procurements
战略和战术采购问题
for international clients."
那是什么意思
And what does that mean?
我不知道  我只是在念屏幕上的字
I-I don't--I was just reading the screen there.
泰德连上服务器之后做了什么
Okay, so what did Ted do when he connected to the server?
根本无从而知  他可能发了封邮件
It's impossible to tell. He could've sent an e-mail
或者上了网站
or accessed the web site.
或者黑掉了它
Or he hacked it.
有可能  不管他做了什么  那之后
That, too. Whatever he did, it was the last time
直到他死去  电脑再没人用过了
this laptop was used before he died.
曼哈顿办事处的负责人是谁
Okay, so, who runs the Manhattan office?
安德森·克洛斯
Anderson Cross.
去问问克洛斯先生知不知道泰德想干什么
All right, let's see if Mr. Cross knows what Ted was up to.
我说不好  卡塞尔  也许你妈妈是对的
I don't know, Castle. Maybe your mom's right.
我觉得私奔是个好主意
I think elopement's a great idea.
不用计划  不用列宾客名单
There's no planning, no lists.
我们只需要结婚就行了
All we do is we just get married.
贝克特  我向你承诺  我们完美的婚礼
Beckett, I promise you, there is a perfect date
会有一个完美的日子  我们会找到的
for our perfect wedding, and we will find it.
-相信我  -我相信
- Trust me. - I do.
婚礼的幽默  不错
Oh, wedding humor. Nice.
我们得和安德森·克洛斯谈谈
We need to speak with Anderson Cross.
让我看看他有没有空
Let me see if he's available.
不好意思
Excuse me.
我是卡塞尔
Castle.
理查德  有事要发生了
Richard, something is about to happen.
你要保持镇定
But you cannot react.
对不起  你是哪位
I'm sorry. Who is this?
事关很多人命  记住  保持镇定
Lives are at stake. Don't react.
抱歉  克洛斯先生没接电话
Sorry, Mr. Cross isn't picking up.
他来了
Oh. Here he is.
克洛斯先生  这两个人要见你
Mr. Cross, these people are here to see you.
你们好
Hello there.
我是安德森·克洛斯
I'm Anderson Cross.
你好  我是凯特·贝克特探长
Hi. I'm Detective Kate Beckett.
纽约警察局
N.Y.P.D.
贝克特探长  很高兴见到你
Detective Beckett, so nice to meet you.
这位是理查德·卡塞尔
And, uh, this is Richard Castle.
抱歉  没听清你叫什么
Sorry. I didn't get the name.
理查德  理查德·卡塞尔
Richard. Richard Castle.
不如我们去会议室谈吧
So why don't we go on into the conference room where we can talk?
好的
Yes.
老爸怎么是你
Dad?
什么都别说
Not a word.
我并不是想催促你们
So, I don't mean to rush us,
但过几分钟我还有个约会
but I do have an appointment in a few minutes.
实际上用不了多久  克洛斯先生
Actually, this won't take very long, Mr. Cross.
你认识一个叫泰德·罗林斯的人吗
Um, do you know a man named Ted Rollins?
我想我不认识  怎么了
No, I... I don't believe I do. Why?
他昨晚被杀害了
He was murdered last night.
好吧
Okay.
我不明白这跟我有什么关系
I'm not sure what that has to do with me.
我们查出昨晚7点19左右
Well, we believe that he tried to access your network
他曾试图登录你的网络
yesterday evening around 7:19.
你知道他为什么要这么做吗
Do you have any idea why he would do that?
实际上  我刚刚接到信息技术中心的报告
Well, as a matter of fact, I just got a report from my I.T. people
说昨晚确实有人尝试入侵我们的系统
saying that someone tried to hack into our system
大概就在你说的那个时间
around about that time.
贵公司具体是做什么业务的
And what exactly does your company do?
我们的主要业务是处理百万元级别的货币交易
Well, we basically handle, uh, multi-million dollar
客户包括各大银行
currency transactions for banks,
国际贸易公司和其他国家
international businesses, uh, foreign countries and the like.
也许泰德是想黑进来
Maybe Ted was trying to, uh... tap in and steal
然后从某桩交易中得利
from one of those transactions.
如果真是这样
Well, if he did...
那他就是空手而归了
he was quite unsuccessful.
之前有人入侵过你公司的网络吗
Has anyone tried to hack into your company's network before?
当然  但是我们有强大的防火墙系统
Oh, yes. But we have quite a robust firewall system.
从来未被攻破过
It's never been breached.
你是否可以将昨晚和之前的
Um, well, would you mind giving me copies
入侵者入侵报告给我一份
of your incursion reports along with the ones from last night?
乐意效劳  等下就发给你
Of course. I'll send them right over to you.
谢谢  感谢你的配合
Okay, thank you. Thanks for your time.
很抱歉  克洛斯先生
I'm sorry, Mr. Cross, uh,
我们以前见过吗
have we ever met before?
我没有印象
I don't believe we have.
真的吗  但你看起来很面熟
Really? Because you just seem so familiar.
是吗
Really?
我确实长了张大众脸
Uh-huh. I have one of those faces.
蕾妮发现了些线索  我们该走了
Um, Lanie's got something for us. We should go.
-太好了  -谢谢你
- Great. - Thank you.
不客气  乐意效劳
Not at all. My pleasure.
我可能知道为什么
Okay, so I may know why
泰德两只鞋的鞋带绑得不一样了
one of Ted's shoes was tied differently.
凶手当时是在找东西
The killer was looking for something.
在他的鞋里吗
In his shoes?
没错  泰德死的时候右脚袜子里有一枚硬币
Yep. At the time of his death, Ted had a coin in his right sock.
因为尸体变得僵硬  所以留下了一个印子
Due to rigor mortis, an impression remained,
上面还有模糊的图案  看到没
including these faint markings. You see that?
真的啊
Yeah. Wow.
卡塞尔
Hey, Castle.
你有在听吗
You with us?
有啊  当然有了
Yeah. Yeah, of course.
我们理一下头绪
Uh... let me get this straight.
泰德被枪击后  凶手脱下了他的鞋和袜子
So, after Ted was shot, the killer took off the shoe and the sock,
抢走了硬币  再原样穿好
grabbed the coin and then put the shoe and sock back on?
一定是枚非常值钱的硬币
Must've been a valuable coin.
实际上还真的不是  我将图像增强了一下
Actually, it wasn't. I did some enhancement.
根据硬币的直径和图案
And based on the coin's diameter and the markings,
确定这是一枚伊朗里亚尔
we've identified it as an Iranian Rial,
面值比一美分还小
worth less than a penny.
一枚伊朗里亚尔
Wow, an Iranian Rial, huh?
卡塞尔
Castle?
你没有什么关于国际大阴谋
No... theories on international intrigue
秘密间谍之类的理论要说吗
or covert espionage?
线索太少了  这个时候说那些还为时过早
We really don't have the information to speculate at this point.
好吧
Okay.
你能缩小泰德的遇害地点范围吗
Were you able to narrow down where Ted was killed?
不能  但我确实检查了他的胃部残留物
No, but I did check his stomach contents.
我可以告诉你  死前15分钟左右
And I can tell you this-- approximately 15 minutes before his death,
泰德吃过蛤蜊和油炸饼
Ted ate clams and funnel cake.
你们能相信吗
Can you believe that?
蕾妮  你的工作就是解剖死人
Lanie, you slice open dead people for a living
却觉得这个很恶心吗
and you're grossed out by that?
强大如我也是有弱点嘛
Even I have my limits.
好了  蛤蜊和油炸饼
Okay, fine, uh, clams and funnel cake.
听上去像是游乐场的小吃
That sounds like he had amusement park food.
没错  再加上泰德衣服上的
Right, and the hydraulic fluid
液压液和红色油漆
and red paint on Ted's clothes?
他确实到过游乐场  而且我还知道是哪一个
He was at an amusement park, and I can tell you which one.
你怎么知道的
How?
作为一个嘉年华小吃的行家
Well, as a connoisseur of carny food,
只有一个游乐场
there's only one amusement park
同时提供煎蛤蜊和油炸饼
that has both fried clams and funnel cake,
那个游乐场就是
and that park is...
科尼岛
Coney Island.
你们两个心有灵犀的感觉真是毛骨悚然
Okay, you two creep me out when you do that shared brain thing.
呃  我
Uh, I...
我忘了  我得去出趟版商那里
Hey, I-I forgot I had to... drop by my publisher's.
看看...排版毛条
We gotta look at the... galleys.
是另一本...德里克·斯道姆小说的
There's another-- uh, for the Derrick Storm... novels.
有个排版毛条...
There's the galley, and, uh...
太好了  谢谢  贝克特
Great. Thanks. Hey, Beckett!
科尼岛维护部负责人说
The head of Coney Island's maintenance staff
只有一个地方会出现液压机液体和油漆
said that the only place there would be hydraulic fluid,
就是过山车下方的维修区域
and paint is the repair facility under the roller coaster.
让公园保安部去检查一下
Okay, let's have park security check it out for us.
已经查了
They have,
发现了血迹
and they found blood.
这肯定就是泰德被杀的现场
Well, this is definitely where Ted was killed.
为什么在这儿  他来干什么
Why here? What was he up to?
油炸饼摊主记得泰德
Yo, funnel cake vendor remembered seeing Ted.
说他买了油炸饼后向这边走了
Said he got his food and walked in this direction.
有人同行吗
Was he with anyone?
-他没看到  -凶手一定是跟踪至此
- Not that he saw. - Killer must've followed him.
说不定是他们约好在这见面
Or maybe they came here to meet.
凶手为什么不留下尸体
Yeah, why wouldn't the killer leave the body here?
为什么要费劲带回曼哈顿
Why would he drag it all the way back to Manhattan
放回被害人家里
to the victim's own apartment?
误导我们
To throw us off his trail.
也可能凶手之所以不想暴露犯罪现场
Or maybe the killer didn't want us to find the crime scene
是因为现场有能指明他犯罪的证据
because there's something here that ties him to the murder.
这里有监控录像吗
Do they have security cameras here?
只有一个监控着南门
Just that one covering the south entrance.
和公园保卫处谈谈
Okay, let's talk to park security.
让他们提供一份监控录像
Get them to give us the surveillance footage.
给你
There you go.
-上帝保佑你  -谢谢
- God bless you, man. - Yeah.
坐我后面
Sit behind me.
没想到还会再见你
Never thought I'd see you again.
泰德·罗林斯
Ted Rollins.
你的被害人  你都知道些什么
Your victim. What have you learned?
我都知道...
What have I le--
抱歉  一年前  我都还不认识你
I'm sorry, until a year ago, I had no idea who you were,
你现在突然出现
and now you come out of the blue,
就说一句
and the only thing you have to say is,
你都知道些什么
"What have you learned?"
总该问句  儿子  过的怎么样吧
How about a, "Hello, son. How you been?"
你在感情用事  现在不是时候
You're getting emotional. Now is not the time.
是吗
Really?
40年来都不是时候
Cause it's been about 40 years,
那什么时候合适
so when would be a good time?
就我的工作而言  永远不合适
With what I do? Never.
你忘了巴黎的事了吗
Or did you forget what happened in paris?
没有  怎么会忘
No. How could I forget?
那就要以之为鉴
Then stop acting like you did.
你知道我的工作  身份
You know what I do. You know who I am.
我不谨慎就会带来伤亡
I let my guard down, people die.
比如泰德
People like Ted?
他到底是谁  凶手又是谁
So who was he really? Who killed him?
你得先告诉我你的消息
You need to tell me what you know.
你不信任我
You don't trust me.
信任比子弹更危险
Trust kills faster than bullets.
马上有大事要发生
Look, there's a storm coming,
我要是不阻止  就会出现更多伤亡
and if I don't stop it, a lot more people are gonna die.
告诉我你得到的信息
Just tell me what you know.
他在科尼岛的过山车下被枪杀
He was shot at Coney Island under the roller coaster.
袜子里有一个硬币
There was a coin in his sock,
是个伊朗里亚尔
an Iranian rial.
硬币在你这吗
Do you have the coin?
凶手拿走了
No, the killer took it.
为什么  拿走硬币意味着什么
Why would he do that? What does that mean?
意味着我要走了
It means I gotta go.
有什么新消息及时发短信
If there's any update, text me.
说要见面  30分钟内我就会来这等你
Say you need to meet, and I'll be back here within 30 minutes.
别跟任何人提起我
Don't tell anyone about this, about me.
你的未婚妻也不行
Not even your fiancee.
你怎么知道我们订婚了
How'd you know we were engaged?
虽然我做的不好
Well, I may not be good at it,
但我还是你父亲
but I am still your father.
现在起保持缄默
Now keep your mouth shut,
免得我们性命难保
and let's try not to get us both killed.
怎么了
What's wrong?
不喜欢你漫画小说的画作吗
You don't like the artwork for your graphic novel?
不是  画的很好
Oh, no, no, it's great. It's good, it's, um...
是科尼岛没错吧
So we were right about Coney Island, huh?
对  一个谜团解开了
Yes. One mystery solved.
只是它带来了更多谜团
Only it's led us to a few new ones,
比如泰德为什么要去
like what was Ted doing there in the first place?
-确实奇怪  -是令人费解
- Yeah. It's weird. - It's more than weird.
你没觉得这事后面有隐情吗
Something bigger's going on here, don't you think?
你们俩
Hey, guys.
来看看这个
Come check this out.
这是过山车维修区域
This is surveillance from that security camera
入口的监控录像
at the entrance of the roller coaster repair yard.
泰德在晚上8点47分独自进入
Ted enters alone at 8:47 p.M.
在他之前有人进去吗
Did anyone enter prior to that?
没有  但是9点04
No. But about 15 minutes later at
也就是15分钟后有人进去
9:04 p.M., someone does.
等等  暂停  放大画面
Wait. Zoom in and freeze it.
那是安德森·克洛斯
That's Anderson Cross.
天哪  他是凶手
Oh, my god. He's our killer.
凶手就是安德森·克洛斯
This whole time it was Anderson Cross.
泰德肯定是成功入侵他的系统了
So Ted must've hacked into his system,
但他决定亲手解决
and he decided to take matters into his own hands.
不太可能吧
But that doesn't seem likely.
我看他不像那种人
I mean, he really doesn't seem the type.
卡塞尔  你说什么呢
Castle, what are you talking about?
他说谎了  他声称不认识泰德
He lied to us. He told us he didn'tnow Ted,
却出现在犯罪现场
and there he is at the crime scene.
又没看到他实施犯罪
We don't actually see him commit murder.
这个地方的入口也不止一处
There's a number of entrances to that area,
但只有一个摄像头
but there's only one camera.
我只是觉得不该臆断
It just... may not be what it seems.
还有别的解释吗  他就刚好在
So, what? He just happened to be there
泰德入侵他公司系统两小时后去了公园
Two hours after Ted hacked his company?
认定安德森·克洛斯是凶手吗
I'm... just saying that Anderson Cross is the killer?
这只是我们显而易见的选择
It's just the obvious choice.
所有证据都指向同一嫌疑人时
Well, that's usually what happens
都指向同一嫌疑人时  我们就会这样做
when all the evidence points to a suspect.
我们得找他来问话
We have to get him down here.
找出他公司的所有资料
Pull up everything you can on his company.
-这不可能  -怎么了
- This makes no sense. - What?
什么都没了  找不到网站了
It's gone. The site disappeared.
不只是网站  他公司存在的痕迹也不见了
Actually, not just the site. Every trace of the company.
找到安德森·克洛斯
Find Anderson Cross now.
他到底是谁
Who the hell is this guy?
很显然他不是银行家
He's obviously not a banker.
我知道为什么看他那么眼熟了
I know why he looks familiar.
-你去哪儿  -去证实我的想法
- Where you going? - To check something.
接电话  快接电话
Pick up, pick up.
请留言
Leave a message.
-卡塞尔  -妈呀
- Hey, Castle. - Jeez!
老兄  你怎么一惊一乍的
Damn, bro. Why you so jumpy?
我...  没有  我只是...
I'm--dude, I'm not. I'm just...
听了我们的发现之后你就会了  来吧
Well, you will be once you hear what we've found. Come on.
这个安德森·克洛斯
So, this guy, Anderson Cross,
就像你小说里的反派
is like a villain in one of your books.
像是知道我们要去  他的办公室清空了
His office was cleared out like he knew we were coming.
-一点线索都没有吗  -啥也没有
- There wasn't a trace of him? - Nothin'.
就连他的接待员
Even his receptionist.
都是从短工中介雇来的
She was hired from a temp agency.
昨天才开始工作  她一无所知
Just started working yesterday. She doesn't know jack.
大楼管理者也不清楚状况
Neither did the building manager.
他说克洛斯上个月租了那地方
He said that Cross rented the place from him last month,
用支票付了全年的租金
paid for a year's lease with a cashier's check.
所以根本无迹可寻
So it's totally untraceable.
不管这人是谁  他绝非善类
Yeah, whoever this guy is, he's in a different league.
而且我们跟他以前有过交集
And we've crossed paths before.
什么意思
What do you mean?
看看这个  记得这个人吗
Check this out. Remember this guy?
去年阿丽克西斯被绑架的案子
Alexis's kidnapping last year.
天啊  就是他
Damn, that's right. Uh...
目击者在绑架案相关地点
Witnesses kept seeing him pop up
多次看到他出现
at locations associated with her abduction.
而这些地方通常都会出现
And at each one of those locations,
一具死尸
there was a dead body.
我把监控视频传给了一个在总检察长办公室
So I sent the video surveillance to a friend of mine
工作的朋友  他查到了匹配记录
in the A.G.'s office, and he got a hit.
他不能透露细节
Now he couldn't get into details,
但他说这人以前是中情局特工
but he did say that this guy is a former C.I.A. Operative.
等等  以前是
Wait a minute. Former?
对  他未经授权执行刺杀行动
Yeah, he, uh, he was disowned
被中情局撇清了关系
for an unauthorized assassination.
被判处终身监禁  但成功越狱了
He was sentenced to life, broke out,
过程中杀死三名狱警
killed three guards in the process.
这人是政府的通缉犯
This guy's wanted by our government.
我朋友说据传
Now my friend said that the rumor is,
他现在是职业杀手  如果我们找到他
he's working as a hit man. And if we get eyes on him,
希望我们联系总检察长办公室
the A.G.'s office wants us to call them.
到时候他们会派遣突击队
So they can send in a strike team.
这样的人为什么要杀泰德·罗林斯呢
Why would a guy like this wanna kill Ted Rollins?
更重要的是我们怎么能找到他  人家可是间谍
More than that, how are we gonna find a former spy?
掩盖踪迹是他的拿手绝活
He's spent a lifetime covering his tracks.
但泰德有迹可循
Yeah, but Ted hasn't.
他们之间有某些联系
And somehow they're connected.
所以我们该去查
So, we should see
看他有没有留下线索能让我们找到疑犯
if Hansel left any breadcrumbs towards our suspect.
我们得去查泰德生前的所有行踪
We need to retrace every one of Ted's footsteps.
凶手很了解他  还知道他住在哪儿
Our killer knew him well enough to know where he lived.
-他们以前肯定有过接触  -好的
- I mean, they had to have had previous contact.  - Okay.
卡塞尔  你在巴黎见过这个人吗
Castle, did you ever see this man in Paris?
不记得了
Not that I can remember.
不如  你把素描发给我
Why don't you, um, text me those sketches?
我去接阿丽克西斯过来
I'll have, uh, Alexis come over.
看她能不能认出他
See if she recognizes him.
需要我和你一起去吗
Do you want me to come along?
不  不用  我会电话联系你
Uh, no. No, no. That's--I'll call you.
你还好吧
You okay?
很好
Yeah.
我什么也没查到  你呢
So I'm coming up with a whole bunch of nothing. You?
你看  这是泰德地铁卡记录
Check it out. It's a printout of Ted's MetroCard.
看看他昨天怎么去的科尼岛
Look how he got to Coney Island yesterday.
他在33街和公园南大道站
He swiped his card
刷了地铁卡
at the 33rd and Park Avenue South Station.
很可能坐的6号线转的N号线  怎么了
Probably took the 6 to the N train. So?
看看他过去两周的记录
So look at his swipes for the past two weeks.
他总是坐地铁
He kept going back and forth
在33街和公园南大道站来来回回
to that subway stop at 33rd and Park.
没错  可是他单位和家都不在那儿
Exactly. And he didn't work, live,
在那一带也没什么认识的人
or know anyone in that area.
-我们去看看他去那儿干嘛  -走吧
- All right. Let's get up there and see what he was doing. - All right.
理查德  你提前回家了
Oh! Richard, you're home early.
来杯"液化人间天堂"怎么样
Care for a glass of liquefied heaven?
喝了头发好  牙齿也...
Good for your hair, good for your te--
出什么事了
Richard, what is it?
他是我爸  我当然相信他
Of course, I believed him, because he's my father.
特别是在巴黎的事情发生后
Well, especially after Paris.
你更加没有理由不信他了
I mean, why wouldn't you?
但他利用了我  为了提前知道调查进度
But he used me--to stay ahead of the investigation,
以便知道何时跑路
to know when to make a run for it.
如果他是无罪的
If he's innocent,
为什么不去公园
why didn't he show up at the park?
理查德  听着
Richard, look...
关于他  我们唯一确定的就是
The only thing we really know about him
我们根本不了解他
Is that we don't know him.
我  我和他只有过一夜风流
Me? I had one night with him.
你呢  你和他只在巴黎相处过一天
You? A day in Paris.
你该依靠你信任的人
Lean on the people you trust.
打电话给凯瑟琳
Call Katherine.
告诉她发生了些什么
Tell her what's going on.
我去开门
I'll get that.
如果他讲的是真话呢
And what if he's telling the truth?
如果他没说真话呢
What if he isn't?
你好  玛莎
Hello, Martha.
好久不见
It's been a while, huh?
你来这干嘛
What the hell are you doing here?
抱歉没有赴约
Sorry to miss our meet,
但是  那时我正忙着被人射杀呢
but, uh, I was a little busy getting shot.
天呐  快进来
Oh, my god! Come in.
你气色不错
You look good.
是啊  你可不如以前好
Yeah, well, you've looked better.
对不起
Sorry.
我按你说的  把所有东西都煮沸消过毒了
Okay, I boiled everything just like you said.
我可得警告你  我唯一一次
But I have to warn you, my only other experience
手术经验还是在一次棋盘游戏中
with surgery involved a board game
我出了错  那人的鼻子都被点着了
and a guy whose nose lit up when I made a mistake.
你把酒拿过来了吗
Did you bring the booze?
是的  在这呢
Yeah. No, right here.
你要弄点来减轻疼痛吗
You want something to dull the pain?
不  我需要你保持镇定
No, I want you to steady your nerves.
-喝一大口  -好主意
- Take a swig. - Good idea.
好吧
Okay.
现在  在伤口上切开一个小口
Okay, now, make an incision through the wound
-一英寸左右  -拿好
- about an inch long. - Here you go.
好的
Okay.
一英寸左右
About an inch.
好了
Okay.
那好  接下来的就有意思了
All right, now here comes the fun part.
你小心点  我是认真的  小心地把子弹取出来
Carefully, and I do mean carefuy, pull the slug out.
帮帮忙
But do me a favor.
尽量别点着我的鼻子
Try not to make my nose light up, huh?
好的
Right.
那就好
Okay.
我好像找到了
I think I have it.
我找到了
I got it.
没成功  不好意思
I don't got it. Sorry.
小心点  理查德
Careful, Richard.
现在你知道这样行不通
Now that you know how not to do it,
那我们就换一种方法
Let's try the other way.
好的
Yeah, right.
-我帮你擦擦  -谢谢
- Okay, let me just get you here. - Thank you.
好了
Okay.
我应该够到了
I think I have it.
好的
All right...
我想我
I think I...
-我取出来了  -真棒
- I have it. - Bravo!
干得不错
Real good.
-好啦  -太好啦
- There we go. - Oh, we go.
玛莎  把针和线递给我
Martha, hand me the needle and thread.
好的  在这
Uh... okay, here it is.
好的
And there we go.
你之前自己缝过吧  我可以这么认为吗
All right, you've stitched yourself up before, I take it?
至少这次我有根针
At least this time I got a needle.
你想跟我们说说  你怎么中弹的吗
So, you wanna tell us how you got shot?
不太想
Not particularly.
那就说说你逃狱的时候
What about the three guards you murdered
杀掉的三个狱警吧
while escaping from prison-- you wanna tell us about them?
不要相信你看到的一切
Don't believe everything you read.
你没有杀掉他们
So you didn't kill 'em?
我是系统外人员
I work outside the system,
也就是说我得有个有效的掩护身份
which means I need an effective cover.
受雇于人的杀手  被政府通缉
Hired assassin, wanted by Uncle Sam...
提供了各种可能
Opens a lot of doors.
卡塞尔
Castle?
糟了
Crap.
我来看看阿丽克西斯有没有想起
Hey, so I thought I'd see if Alexis remembers
关于画像上那人的一些事情
anything more about the man from the sketches.
关于画像上的那个人
Yeah, about the man in the sketches, um...
有些事情你应该知道
something you should know about him.
什么
What?
他是你将来的公公
He's your future father-in-law.
很高兴再见到你  凯特
Nice to see you again, Kate.
凯瑟琳
Katherine,
我很想说事情并不是你看到的那样
I wanna say this isn't what it looks like,
可事实就是这样
but it is.
-我本打算告诉你的  我发誓  -什么时候
- I was gonna tell you. I swear. - When?
你把他包扎好  把他送走之后吗
After you patched him up? Sent him on his merry way?
他被政府通缉
He's wanted by the government.
你这是在窝藏逃犯
You are harboring a fugitive.
那是他的掩护身份
That's just his cover.
你怎么知道的  就因为他这么说了吗
And you know that, how? Because he told you?
还因为巴黎  更因为他是我的父亲
Because of Paris. And because he's my father.
他不是你父亲
He is not your father.
他很久以前就做出选择了
He made that choice a long time ago.
现在这个人是我的嫌疑犯
This man is my suspect.
你知道我该怎么做  是吗
Now you know what I have to do, right?
乖乖  她可真是个暴脾气
Boy, she is a spitfire, this one.
很高兴我们在同一战线上
I'm glad we're on the same side.
谁说我们在同一战线
Who says we're on the same side?
不好意思  他不愿意躺着不动
I'm sorry. He wouldn't stay put.
-理查德  我需要你的电脑  马上  -好的
- Richard, I need your laptop. Now. - Right.
不行  你现在能做的就是
No. The only thing that you are getting
带上手铐跟我回局里
is a ride to my precinct in handcuffs.
你不能逮捕我
You're not gonna arrest me.
真的吗  为什么
Really? Why?
因为你想知道答案
Because you want answers.
如果带我走  你什么都得不到
And if you take me in, you're not gonna get any.
联邦调查局的人会插一脚  你什么都做不了
The feds will swoop in. You won't have anything,
而我将浪费宝贵的时间
and I'll have lost valuable time.
你想找出杀害泰德的人  我也想
You want Ted's killer? So do I.
现在还有很多比谋杀更重要的事情  等着去解决
There's a hell of a lot more at stake here than murder.
那你就得告诉我是什么事情
Then you're gonna have to tell me what it is.
中情局出现重大的特工背叛事件
There was a massive breach at the C.I.A.
有人黑进网络  将含有深入敌方内部特工
Someone hacked the files containing the identities
真实身份的资料盗走了
of our deep cover operatives.
你知道是谁干的吗
Do you know who?
不知道  但肯定是内部高层的人
No. But it was an inside job at the highest level.
这也是他们找我的原因  因为我是系统外的人
That's why they called me. Because I'm outside.
我的任务就是找到内奸  找回文件
My orders were to find the mole and recover the files.
这些和泰德有什么关系
What does any of this have to do with Ted?
泰德是我的得力助手
Ted was one of my best guys.
我让他帮我找到"双子星"
I recruited him to help me find Gemini.
"双子星"
Gemini?
那个内奸的代号
Code name for the mole.
他是打算卖掉这份特工名单
He was planning on selling the D.C.O. lists.
但我们找不到他
But we couldn't find him.
如果这些文件泄露出去
If these files get out,
后果将十分严重
the consequences will be very real.
在昨天我们有了进展
Then yesterday we had a breakthrough.
泰德查出了买家的身份  发信号要见我
Ted identified the buyer and he signaled me to meet
以便告诉我他的发现
so he could tell me who it was.
但是
But, uh...
但是双子星抢先到达见面地点
but Gemini got there first.
是他杀了泰德
He killed Ted.
这下让我完全没了头绪
Leaving me S.O.L.,
直到你跟我说了伊朗里亚尔币的事
until you told me about the Iranian rial.
-你把里亚尔币的事跟他说了  -我...
- You--you told him about the rial?  - I...
泰德以此确保即便出了意外
Ted left that as a fail-safe message...
买家身份也能传递出去
about the buyer.
没错  传统的谍报手段
Right, it's old school spycraft.
但是双子星也知道这些手段
But Gemini knows all the old tricks,
所以他取走硬币使你不能追查到他
so he took that coin to throw you off his scent.
没错  我一得知伊朗人身涉其中
Yeah, once I found out the Iranians were involved,
我就回溯泰德的行踪  追查到了一间公寓
I traced Ted's trail back to an apartment
在38号东大街  伊朗外交使团驻所对面
on East 38th Street across from the Iranian mission.
不过双子星比我先到一步
Only Gemini got there ahead of me.
然后他伏击了你
And he ambushed you?
从路对面的楼顶
From a rooftop across the way.
我刚一开门  他就猛烈开火
Soon as I opened the door, all hell broke loose.
但我也不是吃素的
But... i'm good at hell.
我支撑着回到了车上  他也紧追不舍
I made my way back to the car, but he was right on my tail.
我不得不把车开进东河里
I had to drive into the east river
以此摆脱他的追击
just to get away from him.
这故事的确很精彩
Look, this is an incredible story,
我算知道卡塞尔一脑子的点子是遗传谁了
and I can see where Castle gets his talent,
但这无法证明你所说的  都是真的
but it doesn't mean that any of what you said is true.
你不信我吗
You don't believe me?
那就看看新闻吧
Turn on the news.
就在数小时前  一场高速追车大战
A high-speed car chase rocked the neighborhood of Murray Hill
震惊莫里山民众
just hours ago.
有多起报警称
According to multiple reports,
追车之前曾有两名身份不明男子
the pursuit began with gunshots
在38号东大街一处公寓里
at an apartment on east 38th street
卷入了一场激烈的枪战
where two unidentified men were involved in a gun battle.
这也证明不了什么
That doesn't prove anything.
不管泰德这小子卷进了什么麻烦
So, whatever our boy Ted was into,
他都在忙一些谍报之类的东西
it's all some crazy-ass spy stuff.
你发现了什么
What makes you say that?
你听说莫里山的那场追车了吧
Well, you heard about that car chase in Murray Hill?
我们就在现场
Well, we're at the epicenter.
位于38号街和第三大道路口处的一间被打成筛子的公寓
It's a shot-up apartment at 38th and 3rd.
就是从这里开始的
It's where it all started.
根据公寓管理员的说法
According to the super,
泰德·罗林斯几周前租下了这间公寓
Ted Rollins rented this place two weeks ago.
从现场的设备来看  他正在进行网络入侵
By the looks of the equipment, he was hacking.
-入侵哪里  -我不知道
- Hacking who? - I don't know.
他装备了一台挺复杂的无线网络嗅探器
He's got a pretty sophisticated wi-fi sniffer here.
所以他肯定正在截听某人的网络通信
So, must've been intercepting internet traffic from someone.
肯定是路对面的伊朗外交使团驻所
The Iranian mission across the street.
泰德具体截获了什么
What exactly did Ted intercept?
不清楚
I don't know.
硬盘不知被谁偷走了
Someone stole the hard drive.
现在能借我你的电脑用用了吧
Can I borrow your laptop now?
电话留言截存  邮件截存
短信截存
这些是伊朗外交使团的进出通讯
These are communications to and from the Iranian mission.
没错
Yep.
而且违法
That's incredibly illegal.
对头
Yep.
这个  泰德给这条做了标记
Okay, here. Ted flagged this one.
这是一封发给伊扎德·拉贾尼的匿名邮件
It's an anonymous e-mail from Izad Larjani.
他是伊朗情报与国家安全部的人
He's part of vevak-- iran's C.I.A.
"终知  来款已收  中央图书馆阅览室
"F.C. Payment received. Central library reading room.
明日晚五点  网络名  无鳔石首鱼"
Tomorrow 5:00 p.m. network name: Kingfish."
这是昨天发送的
This was sent yesterday.
也就是说今天就要行动了
Which means it's going down today.
他通过加密无线网发送潜伏人员名单的时间
He's sending the D.C.O. list over a secured wi-fi connection
大约在  30分钟之后
in... roughly 30 minutes.
中央图书馆是个完美的交接地点
Central library's a perfect location--
是公开场所  电脑用户众多
It's public. Uh, there's lots of people on laptops.
双子星压根不用和买家面对面
Gemini never has to meet with his buyer face to face.
无线信号在室内最远能辐射到二百英尺
Wi-fi signals max out at about 200 feet indoors.
他和买家必须
He and the buyer will have to be
同时身处图书馆之中
in the building at the same time.
但发生了这么多事
Given everything that's happened,
他为什么还要坚持完成交易
why would he still go through with the exchange?
"终知"意思是"最后通知"
"F.C." Means "Final communication."
意味着这条信息发出后所有通讯全被切断
All links have been severed.
就算双子星想收手  他也无法通知买家
If Gemini pulls out, he has no way to tell his buyer.
所以他会不择手段完成交易
He will do anything in his power to make the transfer.
我得走了  我得去阻止他
I gotta go. I gotta stop this.
你疯了吗
Well, are you crazy?!
我们刚从你体内取了颗子弹出来
We just pulled a bullet out of you.
就不能叫别人去吗
Can't you call someone?
这个任务本来就不存在  我也不存在
This mission does not exist. I don't exist.
没有别人可以叫
There's no one to call.
你没有后援吗
Don't you have back-up?
我就是后援
I am the back-up.
-你这个状况完全不  -你不明白
- You're in no condition--  - you don't understand!
这份名单决不能泄露出去
This list cannot get out into the open.
那我们去
Then we'll go.
卡塞尔说得对  你这样根本应付不来
Castle's right. You are in no condition.
但如果我们阻止了他  就能各得所求了
And if we stop him, then we all get what we want.
为了协调行动  我们先过一遍计划
Let's run this just so we know we're all on the same page.
理查德  你该怎么做
Richard, what do you do?
一旦无鳔石首鱼上线  我就登陆进去
as soon as the Kingfish network goes online, I log in,
下载名单
I download the list.
-你不光登陆  还要第一个登陆  -没错
- You don't just log in. You gotta be first.  - Right.
为什么非得要第一个
Why does he have to be first?
因为这样就能把伊朗买家阻塞住
Because it locks out the Iranians
让他无法下载名单
from downloading the list.
好  卡塞尔下载的同时
Right. And while Castle's downloading,
我就用我手机上的无线网分析器追踪信号
I'll track the signal using the wi-fi analyzer on my phone.
用手机就能找到间谍了吗
You could find a spy on your phone?
母亲  现在什么功能的应用软件都有
Mother, there's an app for everything now.
凯特  记住
Now, Kate, remember,
如果你没有战术优势
if you don't have a tactical advantage,
多看他几眼  他是中情局的人
just get eyes on him. He's C.I.A.
如果你能描述他的长相  我就能找到他
If you can describe him, I can find him.
好的  快5点了  我们得出发了
Okay. It's almost 5:00. We should go.
理查德  这对我来说  意义很重大
Richard, this means a lot, kid.
谢谢
Thanks.
-玛莎  我需要你...  -我明白
- Martha, I'm gonna need you- - I know.
-他哪儿都别想去  -好的
- He's not going anywhere. - Okay.
如果他俩出任何意外...
If anything happens to them...
他是个聪明人
He's a smart kid.
她是个出色的警察
And she's good at what she does.
他俩不会有事的
No, they'll be fine.
我保证
I promise.
抱歉  但你的保证实在没什么价值
Forgive me, but your promises don't mean very much.
双子星有可能是这里的任何一个人
Gemini could be any one of these people.
没错
Right.
搜寻无线网络
Scanning for Wi-Fi signals.
没有叫无鳔石首鱼的
I don't see Kingfish.
也许我们来晚了
Maybe we're too late.
你还弹琴吗
You still play?
不怎么弹了
No, not so much anymore.
真可惜  你弹琴很好听
A shame. You were good.
那真是个忘情的夜
That was hell of a night.
是个忘情的夜
Hell of a night.
还记得你当时弹奏的歌吗
You remember the song you played?
《我可笑的情人》
"My Funny Valentine."
都是很久以前的事了
It was a long time ago.
你得躺下
You need to lie down.
-好了  我要去给你叫辆救护车  -不不不
- All right, I am calling an ambulance for you. - No, no, no.
不用  我只是血糖低罢了
No, it's just... my blood sugar's low.
你有没有果汁
You got any juice?
有
Uh, yes.
5点04分  我们失败了
5:04, we blew it.
是吗  还是我们被耍了
Did we? Or did we just get played?
卡塞尔  我知道他是你父亲
Look, Castle, I know he's your father.
如果他是醉翁之意不在酒怎么办
What if there's an ulterior motive to all of this?
无鳔石首鱼信号出现了  快行动
Kingfish is online. Go.
好的
All right.
输密码
Okay.
T # < L
"T," Hashtag, less than, "L."
-大写的L  -大写的L
- Uppercase "L." - Oh. Capital "L."
必须在买家之前连上  快啊
We gotta get online before the buyer. Come on.
我登录了
I'm in.
在以最慢速度下载文件
Downloading the file at slowest speed possible.
你大概有3分钟时间
That gives you less than three minutes.
好的  你待在这
Okay, you stay here.
告诉我还剩多少时间
You tell me how much time I have.
听得见我说话吗
Can you hear me?
能
Yeah.
-能听见  -信号越来越强了
- I can hear you. - Signal's getting stronger.
你还剩2分40秒
You've got 2 minutes, 40 seconds left.
糟了
Oh, no.
还剩不到2分钟
You've got under 2 minutes.
卡塞尔  我在楼梯这里
Okay, Castle, I'm at the stairs
信号又变弱了
and the signal's gotten weak again.
我错过他了吗
Did I pass him?
等等
Wait a minute.
等等  我们是以二维方式在思考
Wait. We are demonstrating two-dimensional thinking here.
就像《星际迷航2: 可汗之怒》里的可汗一样
Like Khan in "Star Trek II: Wrath of Khan."
可汗没有意识到企业号在他下方
Khan didn't realize that The Enterprise was below him.
对  如果我们是企业号
Right. So if we are The Enterprise,
那代表双子星在...
that means Gemini is--
-我们上面  -没错
- Is above us. - Exactly.
现在可不是接电话的时候  母亲
Oh, this is so not the time, mother.
还剩1分15秒
A minute 15 left.
卡塞尔  我在书架这边
Castle, I'm in the book stacks.
很靠近他了
I'm close.
好了  只剩不到1分钟了  你小心
All right, less than a minute. Be careful.
妈妈
Mom!
你看见他了吗  他在那里吗
Do you see him? Is he there?
不
Oh, no.
怎么了
What?
卡塞尔
Castle.
他接了个路由器
He set up some kind of a relay system.
双子星可能在任何地方
Gemini could be anywhere.
什么
What?!
-等等  事情不对劲  -怎么了
- Hang on. Something is wrong. - What?
下载完成了
Well, the download is complete.
但这不是中情局名单
But this is--this is not a C.I.A. list.
这是...是个电话号码簿
This is... this is a phone book.
-理查德·卡塞尔  -卡塞尔...
-Richard Castle. Wow.  -Castle--
很抱歉打扰您  先生
I'm so sorry to bother you, Sir,
但我是您的头号书迷
but I'm, like, your number one fan.
可不可以给我签个名
Can I get an autograph?
我现在没这个闲工夫
Actually, this is really not a good time.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
卡塞尔
Castle?
卡塞尔  在吗
Castle, are you there?
你就是公园里的那个男人  对不对
That was you at the park, wasn't it?
假扮成流浪汉
Dressed as a homeless guy?
你就是双子星
You're Gemini.
跟我走  别弄出动静
Let's go. Nice and quiet.
那个派你来的男人  他是谁
Man who sent you-- who is he?
我不明白你在说什么
Look, I don't know what you're talking about.
我看到你和他在公园见面  他是中情局的吗
I saw you in the park with him. Is he C.I.A.?
那个电话号码簿
The phone book.
你知道不能发真的名单
You knew not to send the real list
因为你只是想把他引出来
because you were trying to draw him into the open.
没错
That's right.
看来他还挺聪明  派了个没价值的家伙来替死
Looks like he was smart enough to send someone expendable.
悬疑小说家  告诉我
All right, mystery writer. Tell me a story.
你的管理人是谁
Who's your handler?
他的名字  他到底是谁
What's his name? Where is he?
我为什么要告诉你
Why should I tell you?
反正横竖都是死
You're just gonna kill me anyway.
是啊  我可以慢慢折磨你  或者给你个痛快
Yeah. But I can slow, or I can kill you fast.
这得看你了
It's up to you.
你还好吧
You all right?
我吗  受枪伤的是你又不是我
Me? You--you're the one who was shot.
又不是第一次了
Wasn't the first time.
-我叫救护车  -别费力气了
- I'll go call an ambulance.  - Don't bother.
不  不  等等
No! No, no, wait.
你为什么这么做
Wha--why would you do that?
这是个任务  我这是在完成任务
That was the mission. That's what I do.
你是怎么找到我的
H-how did you even find me?
你外套左边的口袋
Your left coat pocket.
这是什么  GPS定位器吗
Wha--what is this? Some kind of G.P.S. Locator?
你是怎么--
How did you--
那个拥抱
The hug.
你把这个偷偷放我身上
You slipped this on me.
我得密切关注你的动向
I needed to keep tabs on you.
是啊  拿我做诱饵
Yeah, to use me as bait.
在公寓的枪战之后
Well, after the shoot-out at the apartment,
我知道自己被发现了
I knew I was blown.
但我必须找回这份名单
But I still had to recover this list.
所以为了占上风
So, to keep the upper hand,
你让我和贝克特陷入圈套
you let Beckett and me walk into a trap.
我们可能因此被杀
We could've been killed.
我不会让你俩出事的
I would never let anything happen to you two.
怎么  用你保护泰德的方法保护我们吗
The way you never let anything happen to Ted?
我这么做是有原因的  理查德
There are reasons I have to do what I do, Richard.
有一天你会明白的
One day you'll understand. Hmm?
去找贝克特  告诉她我们抓到凶手了
Now get Beckett. Let her know we have her killer.
卡塞尔  发生什么事了
Castle, what happened?
-快走  双子星在下面  -好的
- Come on. Gemini's down here.  - Okay.
不  不  不  他刚才还在这
No. No, no, no, no. He was here.
一分钟之前他还在这的
He was here just a minute ago.
不用说他肯定会抬走尸体的
Of course he took the body.
是啊
Yeah.
但是留下了双子星的枪
But left Gemini's weapon.
那把枪和杀死泰德的那把枪弹道吻合
That gun was a ballistics match to the one that killed Ted.
枪的注册登记名字是
It's registered to...
托尼·布莱恩
Tony Blaine.
我们搜过了他的住所
We searched his place.
找到衣服上的血迹与泰德的血液匹配
Found clothes that tested positive for Ted's blood.
布莱恩无疑就是凶手
Blaine's definitely our killer.
但他是谁
But who is he?
他是政府智囊团的研究员
He's a researcher at a government think tank.
但是一个政府智囊团的研究员
Yeah, but what a researcher at a government think tank
到底卷入了什么事  我们不得而知
is doing involved in all this, we have no idea.
是啊  也许我们永远不会知道
Yeah, we may never know.
别太快下定论  我们对他发出了全境通告
Well, hold on. We've got a B.O.L.O. out on him
而且正在监视他的信用卡
and we're monitoring his credit cards.
-我们会找到他的  -找到后
- We'll find him. - And when we do,
也许他能告诉我们安德森·克洛斯是谁
maybe he can tell us who this Anderson Cross is.
是啊  也许吧
Yeah, maybe.
好的  干得好  伙计们
All right, great job, guys.
谢谢
Thanks.
看来中情局
Well, it looks like the C.I.A.
干净利落地结束这一切
wrapped all this up in a neat package.
是啊  拜我老爸所为
Yeah, with a bow courtesy of my father.
至少杀泰德的凶手已被绳之以法
At least Ted's killer was brought to justice,
从某种程度上说
you know, in a--in a way.
布莱恩杀了泰德
But Blaine killed Ted
但是把他的尸体扔在科尼岛
but left his body at Coney Island.
是我父亲移动了尸体
It was my father that moved the body.
他本可以把尸体扔在随便哪个地方
Now he could've put it anywhere,
但他却把尸体抬到泰德的公寓
but he took it to Ted's apartment.
你知道为什么吗
Do you know why?
把他带进我们的管辖区
To bring him into our jurisdiction.
他想我们跟进这个案子
He wanted us to catch the case
这样他就可以从我这得到案子的信息
so he could work me for information.
也许他只是给自己找个理由
Well, maybe he was just looking for a reason
再见你一面  这就是他的风格
to see you again, and this was his way.
我一直犯糊涂  以为他就是我的家人
I keep making the mistake of thinking he's family.
但他不是
But he's not.
你才是
You are.
九月份
September.
什么
What?
我们九月份举行婚礼
We're getting married in September.
九月份不冷也不热
It won't be too hot. It won't be too cold.
是在宜居带  太完美了
It's in the Goldilocks Zone. It's perfect.
等等  卡塞尔  那你的巡回售书怎么办
Wait, wait, Castle. What about your book tour?
管它呢
Screw it.
就九月
September.
很好
Okay.
你好  母亲大人
Hello, mother.
你好吗
How are you?
很有趣  疯狂的一天
Well, that was fun. What a day.
多年来我一直在想
You know, for years I wondered if your father
你爸是真命天子
was the one who got away.
现在  我终于知道了
Well, now, I finally know.
他从来都不值得你浪费时间
He was never worth your time.
不  他值得
Oh, yes, he was.
我第一次见到他
First time I met him,
他给了我人生最好的礼物  就是你
he gave me the greatest gift of my life--you.
如今这么多年过去了  他又给了我另一个
And now after all these years, he's given me another one.
了结
Closure.
所以...  那你呢  儿子
So... what about you, kiddo?
你还好吗
How are you?
我不知道
I don't know.
你觉得我们会再见到他吗
Think we'll ever see him again?
我倒希望我知道
I wish I knew.